Your Majesty, the remains have arrived.
陛下 ご遺体が到着したと
I was talking with Clovis just now.
今 クロヴィスと話しておった
は？
The project must proceed. At once...
急がなければな 計画を
Jibun wo sekai sae mo
The moment when I might be able...
自分を 世界さえも 変えてしまえそうな
Kaete shimae sou na shunkan wa
To change myself and even the world
瞬間は 何時も直ぐ傍に…
Itsumo sugu soba ni
It's always right there at my side
Kakusenu iradachi to
Even as I stood still, looking at myself
隠せぬ苛立ちと
Tachitsukusu jibun wo mitsume
With undisguised frustration
立ち尽くす自分を 見つめ
Mayoi nagara nayami nagara
Feeling lost, feeling anguished
迷いながら 悩みながら
Kuyami nagara kimereba ii sa
Feeling mournful, deciding what to do
悔やみながら 決めればいいさ
Kimi ga kureta kotoba hitotsu
All it took was a single word from you
君がくれた 言葉ひとつ
Tomadoi wa kiesari
And my uncertainty vanished
戸惑いは消え去り
Karappo datta boku no heya ni hikari ga sashita
You let the light shine into what was my empty room
からっぽだった 僕の部屋に 光が射した
Miageta oozora ga
The sky I had been looking up at...
見上げた大空が 青く澄み切って行く
Aoku sumikitte yuku
Cleared and turned blue
Tozashita madowo hiraku
And I decided to throw open...
閉ざした 窓を 開く事を決めた
Koto kimeta
The windows that were kept closed
Jibun wo sekai sae mo
The moment when I might be able...
自分を 世界さえも 変えてしまえそうな
Kaete shimae sou na shunkan wa
To change myself and even the world
瞬間を 感じる今ここに…
Kanjiru ima koko ni
I feel it right here with me
THE STOLEN MASK
Why's an Eleven here?!
見た見た？
どうしてイレヴンが？
容疑者だったよね
He was a suspect in Prince Clovis's murder!
クロヴィス殿下のあれ
But the teacher said it was a false arrest!
誤認逮捕だって先生が
Even so, he seems kinda suspicious, doesn't he?
でも どこか怪しいから
捕まったんだろ？
You don't think he's a terrorist, do you?
まさかテロリストじゃないわよね
うっ うん
Hm?! Uh-uh...
Of course not.
そりゃそうだろう
学校だって確認ぐらいはさぁ
Even the school can confirm that.
An Eleven, here...
イレヴンなんて
He's an honorary Britannian.
名誉ブリタニア人
Even so, it's still the same.
だって 同じ事だし…
We shouldn't just be scared of him.
怖がってるだけじゃダメよ
話してみればどんな人か…
If we talk to him,
we can see what he's like!
おっ おぉ
You tend to come on a little strong.
君 行動力あり過ぎ
あ…
はっ
It's been seven years since we used that signal.
７年ぶりに使ったよ このサイン
Let's talk in the attic, right?
屋根裏部屋で話そう
Yeah.
ああ
I'm so glad you're okay.
安心した 無事で
Thanks to you.
If you hadn't protected me then...
お前のおかげだよ そっちこそ…
俺をかばったりしなきゃ
借りを返しただけ ７年前の
I was just returning the favor.
From seven years ago.
ん…
あぁ
What about that girl?
The one in the capsule!
あの子は？　ほら カプセルの
We were separated
during the fighting.
戦闘のドサクサで 離ればなれに
Wouldn't you know more about her?
そっちの方が分かるんじゃないのか？
No. It looks like only the Royal
Guard knew anything about her.
いや 親衛隊以外は誰も
知らなかったみたいで
I see.
そうか
And your name...
Do I still call you Lelouch?
名前 ルルーシュって呼んでも？
Since the records list my
former identity among the dead,
前の俺は 記録上
死んだ事になってるから
I go by the name Lelouch Lamperouge now.
ルルーシュ・ランペルージ
今は そう名乗ってる
I see.
そう
And you? What happened at your court martial?
そっちこそ
軍事法廷はどうなったんだ？
And why did you enroll in this school?
それに ここに入学って
I'm just as surprised!
僕も驚いたよ
まさかルルーシュが居るなんて
I had no idea you were here. You see...
そのぉ 捜査を正しく行うよう
取り計らってくれた人が居てね
Someone arranged for me
to get a proper investigation.
They said that a 17-year-old
should be in school.
その人が 17歳なら学校に
行くべきだって
Were all of these painted by Clovis?
これ全てクロヴィス兄様がお描きに？
はい
Yes.
Such gentle colors...
So typical of my brother, wasn't it?
優しい色… これが兄様だったのですね
We've successfully identified the guerrillas.
ゲリラのあぶり出しに成功しました
Right, now determine the location of their hideout!
よし アジトの位置を推測
情報を総督に送れ
Get that intel to the viceroy!
Yes, my lord!
イエス マイ･ロード
まさか
It can't be!
Cornelia?!
コーネリアが？
Relics from a past age...
旧時代の遺物がっ
Darlton! In here, correct?
ダールトン この奥だな？
Yes, my lady. What about you?
Do you require us?
はい いかが致しますか 我々も…
Not for this level of resistance.
この戦力差なら必要ない
Understood.
分かりました
Surrender at once, foolish Elevens!
投降せよ 愚鈍なイレヴンども
Damned Brit!
ブリキ野郎が！
Zero doesn't seem to be here.
ゼロは居ないようだな
Killing them one by one won't settle anything...
１つずつ潰しても埒があかないか ふん
Let your bodies rot in here, then!
お前達はここで朽ち行け
I'm home, big brother.
ただいま お兄様
Welcome home, Nunnally. Sayoko.
おかえり ナナリー 咲世子さん
I brought you a present today.
今日は 俺からプレゼントがあるんだ
Oh? What can it be?
まあ 何かしら
ふっ
あ…
あっ
あぁ！
This hand!
この手…
Thank heaven.
よかったぁ
やっぱり無事だったんですね
I knew it. You're all right!
It's been a long time, Nunnally.
久しぶりだね ナナリー
You'll stay the night, won't you, Suzaku?
スザクさん 今日は泊まって
いけるんでしょう？
Suzaku's a student at the school now.
スザクはもうこの学校の生徒なんだ
だから いつでも会えるよ
So you can visit him all the time now.
Really?!
本当に？
I do have work to do for the military
though, so it can't be every day.
軍隊の仕事があるから
毎日は無理だけどね
You... You're still in the military?
軍隊 続けるんですか？
大丈夫 技術部に配置換えして
もらったから そんなに危なくないよ
It's all right.
I've been assigned to an engineering
unit, so it's not that dangerous.
そうか 技術部か
I see. An engineering unit, huh?
Wait, I'll help you.
あっ 手伝うよ
You just sit down.
座ってろって ７年前と違って
こっちがホストなんだ
Unlike seven years ago,
we're your hosts now.
うん
You've really mellowed since then.
お前 なんか おとなしくなったな
And you've gotten a lot rougher.
君はガサツになった
ふっ はいはい
Indeed!
ん！
Didn't I tell you to stay in my room?
部屋に居ろって言っただろ
That man is the Britannian soldier
from Shinjuku, isn't he? Is this wise?
あの男 シンジュクで会った
ブリタニア軍人だろう いいのか？
He's all right. He's...
あいつは大丈夫だ その…
ん？
He's... my friend.
友達… なんだ
Get out, Jeremiah!
出ろ ジェレミア
Lord Guilford! You understand, then?
ギルフォード卿
分かって頂けたのですね
I do, as far as suspecting you of treason, Mr. Orange.
謀反の疑いに関してはな オレンジ君
ぬはっ
However, the fact is that you
Purebloods allowed Zero to escape.
それに君達 純血派がゼロを逃した
事実もある
位を３つほど下げる事にした
You have been demoted three ranks.
うぅ…
You have two choices.
君には選択肢が２つある
One, either start all over as a pilot,
or you can cultivate an orange farm!
一パイロットからやり直すか
オレンジ畑を耕すかだ
うわっ
Come visit again. Nunnally would like that.
また来いよ ナナリーも喜ぶ
Sure. But...
うん でも
ん？
Lelouch, we shouldn't be
seen together at school.
ルルーシュ 僕ら学校では他人でいよう
Why?
なんで？
How would you explain it?
どう説明するんだ？
Being friends with an honorary Britannian...
名誉ブリタニア人と友達だって
下手すればバレてしまう
If we aren't careful, your secret will get out.
About your being royalty.
君が皇子だった事が
はっ
The same goes for Nunnally, right?
ナナリーもそうだろ
これ以上は 君達に迷惑な…
I don't want to cause
you two any trouble...
お前は この前も他人の都合
Putting others before
yourself again, huh?!
Again?
この前？
あっ いや
Nothing...
あ…
Thanks for everything today.
It was fun.
今日はありがとう 楽しかったよ
じゃ また明日
Well, I'll see you later.
Right.
ああ
I'm really glad.
なんか 嬉しいな
え？
I never thought we'd get
another chance to talk like this.
こんな事言える時がくるなんて
思っていなかったから
Did something weird happen to you yesterday?
お前さぁ なんか昨日
おかしくなかった？
You didn't even show up at the student council.
生徒会にも顔出さないし
I didn't do so well on
that world history test.
世界史のテストが悪くってね
I don't believe that!
After all you've...
ま～たまたぁ 今までの…
あっ
It hasn't made the news yet,
まだニュースにはなっていないが
コーネリアにサムライの血が潰された
but the Blood of the Samurai
group was crushed by Cornelia.
They were the largest
group we had in central Japan.
中部最大のグループだったのに一瞬で
なあ ゼロ 俺達このままだと
Look Zero, it won't be long till she comes after us, too.
焦るな 機会を待つんだ
Calm down. We'll wait for our chance.
But!
しかし
I'll contact you next.
次はこっちから連絡する
ふん 馴れ馴れしい奴だな
この辺りが切りどころか
He's getting overly-familiar with me.
Maybe it's time I broke off with them.
ん？
はっ！
Nina?
ニーナさん？
はっ
I'm sorry! Was I being too loud?
ごめん うるさかった？
No, it's fine, really.
But don't you have class?
いえ それはいいんですけど 学校は？
う～ん…
Something wrong?
何か？
Well... How do I put this...
その なんだか怖くて
I'm scared.
Scared?
怖い？
We got a transfer student in our class.
うちのクラスに転校生が来たの
The boy who was accused of killing Prince Clovis.
クロヴィス殿下殺害の容疑者だった人
イレヴンなのよ
He's an Eleven.
あっ
Oh.
ああ いつもありがとうございます
Thanks for being such a steady customer.
Although the account we debit from
has a guy's name on it. Is that all right?
引き落としの口座が男性のお名前ですが
よろしいのですか？
ん？
Is this where you hide your mask?
仮面の隠し場所か？
Unlike my Geass, this is physical evidence.
ギアスと違って
こいつは物的証拠になるからな
ん！
Big brother, the tea's ready.
お兄様 お茶を入れたんですけど
あら？　この匂い またピザ？
Oh, that smell... Did you order pizza again?
I'm collecting points.
ポイント貯めてるんだ
すぐに下に行くから
I'll be right down.
Big brother...
お兄様？
ん？
Aren't you getting a little flabby lately?
Like on your upper arms?
最近プニプニーってなってきてません？
二の腕とか
絶対に触るなよっ
Leave it alone.
Ooh, scary!
まぁ怖い
あっははっ
ふ…
ウ ニャッ
あっ
ん？
あれ？
ふぅ やっぱりな
そんな事じゃないかと
I thought as much.
I was wondering if that was going on.
スザクさん つらい目に…
They're being mean to Suzaku.
No, it's just...
いや それは…
あ… 時間がかかるんだ こういう事は
We have to let this be for now.
なんとかならないのですか？
お友達でしょう
Can't you do something? He's your friend!
うっ…
ん？
ニャー
ほわぁっ！
え？
Hey! Give that back!
こらっ　返せ！
Um... What?
えーっと
ニャー
ニャーニャー
えーっ
猫なんかに 猫の分際で冗談じゃない
By a cat... By a stupid, little CAT!
You have got to be kidding me!
I will not be exposed in such a STUPID way!
こんなバカな事でバレてたまるかっ
ん？
Maybe I should...
ひょっとして…
No, I left it alone, like he said.
いやっ あたしは触ってないぞ うん
CODE GEASS
Lelouch of the Rebellion
Yeah, that's right.
ええ そうなんです
It seems a cat took something really important to him.
なんだか猫に大事な物を
取られたみたいで
大事な物って？
Important?
I'm not really sure what it is,
よく分からないんですけど でも
とっても大事な物に違いないんです
but it's definitely important to him! Because...
だって お兄様のあんな素っ頓狂な声
初めて聞きましたもの
I've never heard my brother
speak so... hysterically before!
なんだろう ルルーシュの
大事な物って？
What could be so important to Lelouch?
あ… ラブレター
A love letter?
恥ずかしい写真
An embarrassing photo?
ポエム手帳
A poetry notebook!
ポエム？
Poetry?
にっひひひっ
まっかせてぇ
Leave this to us!
絶対 ルルーシュより先に
取り返してみせるから 先にっ
We'll get it back before
Lelouch can! BEFORE HIM!
ええい こんな時
テロリストどもがいれば
If I had those terrorists with me,
I could plot an encirclement of the enemy!
包囲作戦を展開できるのに
Kallen?
カレン
いやダメだ これ以上疑われるのは
No, forget it.
She's suspicious of me as it is!
はっ どわーっ
あっ あ… くっ
ぬあーっ くっ　醜態だ
What a disgrace!
So anyway, I told him to buzz off!
だからね 私言ってやった訳
Right, right, and then?
うんうん そしたら？
そしたら そいつさぁ
Well, you can guess what happened!
ん？
What's with that cat?
何 この猫？
Isn't that the mask that Zero wears?
これあの仮面じゃない？　ゼロって
まさか こんな所に…
No way. Here?
あっ
見たな！
You saw it?!
え？
忘れろ！　今 見た事は
Forget what you have just seen!
Yes, we understand.
うん 分かったけど
よしっ
Good!
This is Milly Ashford, your student
council president. Find the cat!
こちら 生徒会長の
ミレイ・アッシュフォードです
猫だ！
うっ
Cat?
猫？
Capture the cat which is
running loose on campus!
校内を逃走中の猫を捕まえなさい
Club activities are
suspended for the time being!
部活は一時中断
協力したクラブは予算を優遇します
Participating clubs will
get priority on their budgets!
そして～ 猫を捕まえた人には
スーパーなラッキーチャンス
And whoever catches the cat
gets a super special prize!
生徒会メンバーから
キッスのプレゼントだぁ
A kiss from a member of the student council!
いっ！　うわぁ あっ
うわ あーー！
The student council... Me, too?!
生徒会って 私も？
そうですよね！
Exactly!
いっ！
生徒会に出入りしてるし
You're always going
to the student council!
Her ladyship's lips!
お嬢様の唇
It's not just gonna be a peck on the cheek, is it?
ほっぺたとか そういう
オチじゃないですよね
Just getting one on
the cheek would be fine!
いやー この際ほっぺたでもいい
Wait, we can choose where
we get kissed?! Well, then...
えーっ 場所指定できるの？
じゃーあ
うへっ…
よっしゃー
ALL RIGHT!
よぉー！
No, stop! This will be my first!
やめてよ 私の初めてのっ
The student council members?
Including Lelouch?!
生徒会メンバーって事は
ルルーシュ君もオーケー？
キャ
I'd like one from Milly, actually...
私 ミレイさんがいいなぁ
え…
Don't come out HERE!
こんなとこでカミングアウトしないで
FIGHT! Ooh!
ファイトー オー！
We have the advantage in mobility!
機動力なら こっちが上だ
Look for catnip!
マタタビ探せぇー
Science will win the day!
科学は勝つー
The cat! When you capture the cat,
bring what it's carrying to me!
猫！　猫を捕まえたら所有物は私に
私に 渡しなさっ うっけほっ
To me! To me!
ぬぇー！　会長 余計な事を
President, stay out of this!
Just offering people as prizes!
人を勝手に賞品にして
これだからブリタニアって
That's why I hate Britannians!
うっそ
Oh, really?
あっ！
ホントに？
Yeah. Amazing, huh?
ホントホント すごいでしょう？
すごい信じらんない
Yeah, I can hardly believe it.
Oh, why'd my cover have
to be that I'm sick and feeble?!
もう 病弱なんて設定に
しなければよかった！
あーっ！
Sorry! Are you?!
ごめんなさい そっちは…　はぁー！
Shirley, why are you
dressed like that?!
なんて格好してるの シャーリー
だって 私達のキスがかかってるのよ
Because they're gonna
make us kiss somebody!
あ…
同感
I'm with you!
Nunnally, is there anything
special about this cat?
ナナリー 何か特徴とかないの？　猫の
Let's see...
えーと 足が悪いと思います
足音がちょっと変だったから
I think its leg is hurt.
Its footsteps sounded
a little odd to me.
Anything else?
それと あっ
その猫はこんなふうに鳴きます
Oh, and it meowed like this.
にゃー
Meow!
おぉー！
What a laid-back school.
呑気な学校ですね
喪に伏しているっていうのに
Even though they're
in mourning for the prince...
大丈夫かしら スザク君
I wonder if Suzaku
will be all right here.
Never mind that.
The university here...
そんな事より ここの大学
あっ 話は通してありますから
Oh, I've made the
arrangements with them.
I see. Still, they didn't have to kick out
everything to do with Lancelot, did they?
そう
しっかし ランスロットごと
追い出さなくったってさぁ
Right. I know they said they didn't
want any Numbers, but still...
そうですよねぇ
ナンバーズはダメだって言われても
Sorry I'm late!
おっ待たせぇ
なあ 俺達生徒会が捕まえても
報酬はもらえるんだよな？
Say, do we get the prize if a member
of the student council catches it?
キスの事？　当然！
A kiss?
Of course!
あっ そっか
I see...
たまには出してみますか 本気ってやつ
Once in a while, I get to
show I can be serious!
Hey! No speeding on campus!
こらっ　校内を走るなあ
ニャ～ ニャ
Okay, this'll keep our kisses safe.
これで私達のキスは安泰ね
シャーリーは後ろをお願い
Shirley, you cover the rear.
待って
Wait!
何？
What?
ねえ キスの権利 カレンは誰に使うの
Look, the right to kiss you...
Who would you give it to?
は？
ひょっとして ルル？
It's not Lulu, is it?!
なっ なんでそうなるのよ？
Why would you think that?!
だって あのさ その…
Well, you see... It's just...
あれは…
Isn't that?
あっ！
なっ！
Suzaku!
スザク！
Lelouch?!
You're looking for the cat, too?
ルルーシュ 君も猫を？
ニャー ニャー
Up there...
上か
待てスザク
Suzaku, wait!
お前は帰れっ
Go back!
But the student president
said to catch it!
でも 生徒会長さんが捕まえろって
No, forget it! I'll get the cat!
いいから帰れ 猫は俺が
I was always more
athletic than you!
体を動かすのは僕の方が得意だよ
前に小鳥が逃げた時だって
Remember when that
little bird got out?
Don't dig up ancient history!
古い話を持ち出すな
たった７年前だよ
It was only seven years ago!
Oh, for Pete's sake!
えーっい！
ったく… 相変わらずの体力バカ
He always was crazy about exercise!
Is it true someone's cornered it?
Who spotted it?!
追い詰めたってホントに？
誰が見つけたのよ
あそこ！
Look!
Suzaku!
スザク君
It's okay. Don't be scared.
大丈夫 怖くないから
Suzaku, no!
スザク よせ！
大丈夫 まかせて
It's all right. Leave this to me.
あいつ 昔は もっと個人主義だったのに
He never used to follow the crowd like this!
Whoa!
どあぁー
あっ ああー
あっ ああ
Lelouch!
ルルーシュ
きっ
あっ
あっ くっ
You okay, Lelouch?
大丈夫か？　ルルーシュ
Y-Yeah...
あ ああ
Is it possible those two are?!
あの２人 まさかっ
うっ くっ
あぁ
あっ
ニャー
はぁ
はぁ…　あっ
You seem overly-relaxed now.
安心し過ぎだよ
I'm just a little worn out.
なんか 力抜けちゃって
Oh?
へえー
どうしたんですか？
What's happening?
That transfer student just saved
Lelouch from a close call.
ルルーシュのピンチを転校生が救ったの
あっ あぁ
I thought it was the
same cat as before.
やっぱり この前の猫だったか
あ…
あっ
うふっ
Thank you! You saved Lulu!
ありがとう ルルを助けてくれて
Way to go, Transfer!
やるじゃん転校生
この猫 何か持ってたでしょう？
The cat was carrying
something, wasn't it?
It seemed to have something on its head,
but I didn't get a good look at it.
何か かぶってたみたいですけど
よく見えませんでしたし
いつの間にかなくなっちゃって
It disappeared
while I wasn't looking.
ねえ ルルは？
And where's Lulu?
あっ ああ
Oh. He said he forgot something
and that I should go on without him.
忘れ物があるから 先に行けって
That's it
His embarrassing secret!
それだ！　あいつの恥ずかしい秘密
へっ？
Is that what this
is about, Miss President?
そういう事ですか 会長
あ…
あーあ せっかく弱みを握れると
思ったのにぃ
Oh...
I thought I finally
had something on him.
ルルってカッコつけだから
Lulu's always got
to keep up appearances.
ふっ
ねえ ２人って知り合いなの？
So, do you two know each other?
あっ！
But, he's an Eleven...
だって… イレヴンと
はっ…
いや 僕は…
No, I just...
友達だよ
He's my friend.
へっ
Miss President, would you allow
him to join the student council?
会長 こいつを生徒会に
入れてやってくれないか
えっ！
This school requires
you to join a club.
うちの学校は必ず どこかのクラブに
入らなくちゃならない でも…
But still...
うーん
副会長の頼みじゃ しょうがないわね
How can I refuse a request
from the vice-president?
うふっ
Well, that settles that.
これで 一件落着ですね
お２人とも お耳を
You two, lend me your ears.
え？
えへっ
あっ
Nunnally!
ナナリー？
The reward that Miss Milly promised.
ミレイさんが公約したご褒美です
Since you both did it,
お２人ですから 半人前の私で
我慢してくださいね
you'll just have to be content with
me as a half-member of the council.
All right! Let's celebrate
our catching the cat!
よーし 猫が捕まったお祝いだ
もちろん新人の奢りな
Naturally, the new guy treats us!
Don't sponge off him!
たかるな！
私シャーリーよろしくね
I'm Shirley! It's a pleasure!
あっ俺 リヴァル
Oh, and I'm Rivalz!
And I'm Milly Ashford,
the council president.
生徒会長のミレイ・アッシュフォード
うっ
よろしくお願いします
A pleasure to meet you, too!
And now an address
by his royal majesty,
神聖ブリタニア帝国
第98代ジューイッツ皇帝陛下よりお言葉
the 98th emperor of
the Holy Britannian Empire!
きっ！
All men... are NOT created equal!
人は平等ではない
生まれつき足の速い者 美しい者
親が貧しい者 病弱な体を持つ者
Some are born swifter.
Some, more beautiful.
Some are born to poor parents,
while others are
born sick and feeble!
In birth, in upbringing, in abilities,
all humans are different.
生まれも育ちも才能も 人間は皆
違っておるのだ
そう 人は差別される為にある
Yes, that is why people
discriminate against each other!
And so people fight! They struggle!
And in doing so, they progress!
だからこそ 人は争い 競い合い
そこに進歩が生まれる
Inequality is not wrong!
不平等は 悪ではない
It is equality which is wrong!
平等こそが 悪なのだ
権利を平等にしたＥＵはどうだ？
What of the E.U.,
which made equality a right?
人気取りの衆愚政治に堕しておる
Mob rule by the most popular!
富を平等にした中華連邦は
怠け者ばかり
And the Chinese Federation,
which equalized the distribution of wealth?
A nation of lazy dullards!
But not our beloved Britannia!
だが 我がブリタニアはそうではない
争い 競い 常に進化を続けておる
We fight, we compete!
We continue to constantly evolve!
Evolve. That's a nice word.
進化 いい言葉だ
Britannia alone moves forward!
ブリタニアだけが前へ
未来へと進んでいるのだ
Advancing into the future!
我が息子 クロヴィスの死も
ブリタニアが進化を続けているという証
And so it is, even with
the death of my son, Clovis.
It is proof that Britannia
will continue to evolve.
戦うのだ！
Fight on!
競い 奪い 獲得し支配する
その果てに 未来がある！
Compete, steal, acquire, and dominate!
And in the end,
the future shall be ours!
ALL HAIL BRITANNIA!
オール・ハイル・ブリタニア！
All hail Britannia! All hail Britannia!
So, this is Lelouch's enemy...
ルルーシュの敵… か
オール・ハイル・ブリタニア！
All hail Britannia! All hail Britannia!
Yukedomo kemonomichi
Walking along the animal path
行けどもけものみち 獅子よ虎よと吠え
Shishi yotorayoto hoe
Roaring with the lions and tigers
茜射す空の 彼方にまほろば
Akane sasu sora no kanata ni mahoroba
Paradise lying far across a sky dyed red
幽囚の孤獨に 彷徨う青春は
Yuushuu no kodoku ni samayou seishun wa
To a youth wandering, imprisoned in loneliness
弱さと怒りが姿無き敵ですか
Yowasato ikari ga sugata naki teki desu ka
Are weakness and hatred shapeless enemies?
父を 未だ我は
Chichi yo madaware wa
Oh father, I am still...
己を知りがたし
Onore wo shirigatashi
Learning who I am
Sakidatsu anira no
As I pursue the backs I no longer see
先立つ兄らの
見えない背中を追えば
Mienai senakawo oeba
Of the elder brothers who have gone before me
迷いの一夜に明星は誘う
Mayoi no hitoyo ni
In the night I spend lost
Myoujou wa izanau
The morning star beckons to me
死して終わらぬ
Shi shite owaranu
This will not end in my death
Yume wo kogaredomo
I long for my dream
夢を焦がれども
確かな君こそ我が命
Tashika na kimi kosowaga inochi
My faith in you sustains my life
Reppu no kouya de
In the windswept wilderness
烈風の荒野で 蝶よ花よと生き
Chou yo hanayoto iki
Living with the butterflies and flowers
Tokoshie no haru ni sakisou maboroshi
Blooming together in a mirage of eternal Spring
とこしえの春に 咲き添うまぼろし
Kondaku nojunketsu
If my purity seems muddied
混濁の純潔 この身は汚れても
Kono mi wayogoretemo
And my body seems filthy
心の錦を信じていてください
Kokoro no nishiki wo shinjiteite kudasai
Please believe in the finery within my heart
母よ けして我は
Hahayo kesshite ware wa namidawo misene domo
Oh mother, I will show no tears
涙を見せねども
Ashimoto no
They vanish like...
足下の草に露は消えもせで
Kusa ni tsuyu wa kiemosede
The dew in the grass beneath my feet
否定という言葉すら生ぬるい
The word "repudiate" is half-hearted.
父が… あの男が…
ブリタニアの象徴ならば潰すまで
If my father is the symbol of Britannia,
then he must be crushed utterly!
その道行きに姉上
コーネリアが居るなら 同じ事
And if my sister Cornelia stands in my path,
she will suffer the same fate!
お前達がまだ知らなくても
Even though you don't
know it yet, I have power.
俺は 力を持っている
ギアスさえあれば 俺は１人で！
As long as I possess the Geass,
I can do this by myself!
ATTACK CORNELIA